不管你盯着看多久 他们还是要来
However long you stare at it, they're still coming.
能有人来拜访也是好事
It might be nice to have some visitors.
才不是好事
No, it won't.
我们可以故意让他们不自在
Let's make it horrible for them,
这样就不会久留了
so they don't stay long.
这里环境已经够差了
It's already horrible.
格里把这房子变成动物园了
Gerry's turned this house into a zoo.
别人家可不用天天遛鹈鹕
No other family has to walk a pelican!
天哪 他们想干什么 要今天下午来
God, what are they doing? They're arriving this afternoon!
我们的卧室不够
We don't have enough bedrooms.
我们什么都不够
We haven't got enough anything.
然而你却异常... 轻松
And yet you seem untypically... relaxed.
是啊 你为什么这么高兴
Yes. Why are you so happy?
亲爱的 到了我这个年龄 这种事已经习惯了
Oh, darling, because at my age, nothing and no-one unsettles me.
但你们还是要记得打扫
Oh, do clean and tidy up, though.
赫尔迈厄尼姑妈很挑剔的
Aunt Hermione can be a bit of a thug.
- 我不行 得写书 - 我上班很忙的
- I can't. I'm writing. - Busy day at work.
要去打猎
Shooting.
德雷尔一家 第一季 第四集
那么 你打算什么时候公布我们的关系啊
So, when are we going to tell the world about us?
我们什么关系
What about us?
斯文 如果英式一点 浪漫地说
Well, that we're an item, Sven,
我们就是一对鸳鸯
as we British so romantically call it.
我觉得应该等你亲戚走了再说
I think we should wait until your relatives have gone,
这样我就不用被当小丑看了
so I don't have to be part of this... circus.
天哪 我可没想告诉他们
God, no, I didn't mean tell them.
赫尔迈厄尼姑妈可喜欢管闲事了
Aunt Hermione has a history of meddling.
她就像一个美第奇暴君
She's like a Medici tyrant.
我倒是想见见她
Oh, I'd like to meet her.
我知道他们会抱怨什么了... 这里没有电
I know what they're going to complain about... no electricity.
在天堂 亚当和夏娃有电用吗
Did Adam and Eve have electricity in paradise?
你知道 日子顺利的时候 这里就是天堂
You know this is paradise... on a good day.
我也知道
And I know.
但他们知道吗
But will they?
早上好 德雷尔女士
Kalimera, Mrs Durrells!
早上好 斯皮罗斯
Ah, kalimera, Spiro.
也许你能帮我一个忙 我需要一个廉价发电机
Maybe you can help me. I need a cheap generator.
怎么不用蜡烛了
What's wrong with candles?
蜡烛光很柔和 不太容易显丑
It's a soft light, reduces the ugliness.
我们有客人从英国来
We have guests coming from England.
更多的英国人 好极了
More British people! Swell!
没问题 我给你找一个发电机去
Yes, I'll find you a generator.
斯皮罗斯 没了你 我们可怎么办啊
What would we do without you, Spiro?
- 想都不敢想 - 是啊
- It doesn't bear thinking about. - It doesn't.
德雷尔女士
Mrs Durrells?
你为什么这么开心
Why are you so happy?
你还记得我们初次见面时
Do you remember when we first met
你说自己讨厌那些成天喝杜松子酒的英国人
and you said you hated all those Brit exiles sipping G&Ts?
那你这几天最好离我家远远的
Well, you'd better steer clear of my house for a while!
总之呢 别惊讶 斯文和我已经...
Anyway, deep breath, Sven and I are...
- 什么... 发生了什么 - 没什么
- What... What's happened? - Nothing.
但你的眼睛都红了
But your eyes are all red.
有什么办法呢 绿色的美景也没什么效果
Well, why not? Green's not bringing me much luck.
哦...
Oh...
我... 以为自己怀孕了 结果没有
I, erm... I thought I was pregnant and I'm not.
哎 佛罗伦斯
Oh, Florence!
- 你们尝试多久了 - 十一年零五个月
- How long have you been trying? - 11 years and five months.
我觉得没什么希望了
I don't think it's going to happen.
可这过程很美好啊
Well, think of the fun you've had trying.
先不管这个了 你和斯文怎么了
Anyway, so, yes, you and Sven...
别告诉别人 我们接了吻 还干了点别的
Don't tell anyone, but, well, we've kissed, and... A bit more.
这段感情是认真的
I think it's serious.
我不想毁了它
I just don't want anything to ruin it.
你好 她在那儿
Oh, hello. She's there!
请对我们友好一点啊
Please be nice to us.
赫尔迈厄尼姑妈 欢迎
Aunt Hermione! Welcome!
下午好 路易莎
Good afternoon, Louisa.
还有普鲁表姐和杰弗里
And Cousin Prue! And Geoffrey!
见到你们真高兴
Oh, what an absolute pleasure.
要是还要闷在船里 我可要疯了
If I have to sit and look out of another window, I'll scream.
- 你们一定累坏了 - 没有
- You must be exhausted. - No.
我可累坏了
I'm exhausted.
你们这些外国人就是这样 动不动就累
That's the thing about your foreigner. It's exhausting.
我的外国友人斯皮罗斯可以开车带我们回家
Well, my foreigner friend Spiro is going to drive us home.
- 除非你们想住在旅店 - 别开玩笑了
- Unless you'd prefer a guest house. - Ridiculous!
还有一个人呢
There's one more.
- 南希 - 没想到吧
- Nancy! - Surprise!
拉里怎么样
How's Larry?
见了你肯定会乐开花
Well, all the better for seeing you, I'm sure!
这边请
Well, erm, this way!
- 你好 - 你好
- Hairete. - Hello.
- 啊 你的手真粗糙啊 - 什么
- Oh, what rough hands you have. - Huh?
那是小红帽里的一句话
It's from Little Red Riding Hood.
这个倒是很细腻 我们不能这样
Mm, that isn't. We mustn't.
会惹上麻烦的
We'll get into trouble.
我特别特别地想你
I think about you... very much.
如果是这样的话...
Oh. Well, in that case...
这数量快赶上动物园了
An immoderate volume of creatures.
是啊 都是格里收集的 火鸡是打官司赢的
Yes. Gerry collects them. And we won the turkeys in a court case.
动物就是长着腿的细菌传染源 他们安全吗
Animals are walking germ dispensers. Are they safe?
大部分是安全的
Mostly.
拉里 亲爱的 你俩休息休息
Larry, darling, put her down.
别管我们
Don't mind us.
我听说你想当作家 劳伦斯
I hear you aspire to being a writer, Lawrence.
不光是想 他现在就等着出版商确认
More than aspire. He's just waiting for the publisher to confirm
把他的小说发布出去了
that he's going to put his novel out.
如果他不忙着接吻 会亲口告诉你的
He'd tell you himself if he wasn't doing that.
这是鲁格勒斯雅 她时不时地来帮帮忙
This is Lugaretzia. She helps us out occasionally.
她很友善
She's lovely.
马戈 亲爱的 告诉大家你的工作
Margo, darling, tell everybody about your job.
我是马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人的女伴
I'm companion to the Countess Mavrodaki.
这对你的智力可没什么帮助
That will hardly stretch your mind.
等等 莱斯利...
Ooh, and Leslie...
好吧 他跑了
Well, he's gone.
拉里 拜托 带她上楼去吧
Larry, for God's sake, take her upstairs.
我有个疑问 路易莎 为什么你们还呆在这里
The question is, Louisa, why are you all still here
而不是回英国
rather than in England?
因为我们喜欢这里
Because we like it here.
- 杰拉尔德呢 - 杰拉尔德很喜欢博物学
- Where's Gerald? - Gerald is very interested in natural history.
这是一种科学 所以他可能出去收集...
It's a science, really, so he is probably out gathering
- 那是一头驴吗 - 研究材料
- Was that a donkey? - research material.
你们外国人喜欢驴
Your foreigner loves a donkey!
你们好
Hello.
我讨厌野生动物
I hate wildlife.
那是什么声音
What is that noise?
拉里撞到他的脚了
Larry stubbing his toe.
真惨 南希也撞到了
Oh, no. Now Nancy's stubbed hers!
他们结婚了 为什么不能住一间卧室呢
They're married. Why don't they share a bloody bedroom?
很明显 因为杰弗里打鼾
Because Geoffrey snores, apparently,
就像牛羚被猎杀了一样
like wildebeest being murdered.
他的妻子普李...
And his wife Prune...
是普鲁 不是普李
It's Prue, darling, not Prune.
她害怕什么啊
What's she so scared of?
是我的话 害怕一时没忍住
I'd be scared of snapping
在杰弗里睡着的时候把他敲死
and clubbing Geoffrey to death in his sleep.
他们为什么都这么招人厌啊
Why are they all so horrid?
他们不是招人厌 只是...
They're not horrid, they're just...
最好呆在英国别出来
better in captivity, in England.
太黑了
It's very dark.
你确定这里没电吗
Are you sure there isn't any electricity anywhere?
那你等一下 我去沙发底下找找
Wait a minute, I'll, erm, I'll just check under the sofa.
我当然确定啊 普鲁 这是我的家
Of course I'm sure! I'm sorting it out, Prue!
谁快把那东西带走
Somebody move that away from the house!
我能听见隔壁房间 你儿子和他的女友
I can hear your son and his lady friend in the next room
正在体验... 肉体关系
having... carnal relations.
他们真幸运
Well, lucky them!
要是所有关系都那么有趣就好了
If only all relations were that much fun.
你不是讨厌自行车吗
I thought you hated bicycles?
我只是想赶快逃掉
Oh... I was so desperate to escape.
骑山羊走我都愿意
I would've saddled up a goat and ridden it.
这就是家庭关系啊
Oh, families.
痛苦多 欢乐少
More pain than pleasure.
这话给佛罗伦斯说吧
Well, tell that to Florence.
她告诉我她怀不上孩子
She confessed to me that they can't have children.
真惨啊
Oh, how sad.
但她能从工作和友谊中找到安慰
But there's consolation in work... and friendship.
如果你想推倒我
Well, if you feel the urge to ravish me,
我准了
you have my full permission.
听着 我会珍惜你对我的欣赏
Listen, I will always respect your honour.
先别管那么多了
Oh, let's not worry too much about that.
德雷尔女士 你在吗
Mrs Durrells? Hello?
我无意打扰 但是我找来了一台发电机
I don't want to intrude, but I have found you a generator.
我... 我什么都没看见
I... I saw nothing!
斯皮罗斯 我要请你保守这个秘密 可以吗
Spiro, I have to ask you to keep this a secret. Can you do that?
莱斯利 去叫拉里
Leslie, go and get Larry.
我才不去他那个淫窝
I'm not going into his den of vice.
- 我把他叫来了 - 你能长话短说吗
- I've got him. - Can we make this short?
我们非得在这里说吗 这里满是...
Do we have to talk here? It's full of...
- 它们是什么鬼 - 我的褐鼠
- What the heck are they? - My brown rats.
- 你想抱抱它吗 - 你觉得呢
- Do you want to hold one of them? - What do you think?
你要说什么 晚饭可不会从天上掉下来
What's this about? Supper needs shooting.
我要公布一件事 省得斯皮罗斯说出来
I have an announcement to make, before Spiro blurts it out.
- 你要和斯皮罗斯在一起了吗 - 没有
- You're getting together with Spiro? - No!
不是
No.
斯文和我... 关系不仅仅是朋友了
Sven and I... are becoming more than good friends.
- 我们早知道了 - 我们并不知道
- Oh, we knew that. - No, we didn't!
- 我早就知道了 - 这太让人激动了
- I knew that. - This is so exciting!
父亲去世已经... 八年了
It's been... eight years since Father died.
是的 并且 我很喜欢斯文
Well, yes. And... Well, I'm very fond of Sven.
这么久了 终于遇到了心上人
And it has been a long time coming.
还有戴维斯先生呢
There was Mr Davis.
是的 戴维斯是个错误
Yes, Mr Davis was a mistake,
一般来说古董商都不适合我
as antique dealers often are.
你不需要别人 你有我们呢 还有我
You don't need anyone. You have us, and me.
莱斯利 亲爱的 别不开心啊 我还是爱你的
Leslie, darling, don't be upset. I still love you.
格里 亲爱的 说句话啊
Gerry, darling, say something.
- 你觉得他会给我他的一只羊吗 - 不
- Do you think he'll let me have one of his goats? - No.
还有 千万别给赫尔迈厄尼姑妈说
Oh, and do keep this from Aunt Hermione.
她要是拿这个说事 咱们谁也受不了
She could make our lives very unpleasant if she wanted to.
她为什么要这样
Why would she do that?
因为她是家里的老大
Because she's the head of the family,
还拼命要展现这一点
and she likes everyone to know it.
莱斯利 有什么事你藏着没说
Leslie, you're hiding something.
跟你母亲有关吗
Is it to do with your mother?
妈妈不让我们说出去
I can't say. Mum told us to keep quiet.
我感觉跟男人有关 是希腊人吗
I sense it's a man. Is he Greek?
瑞典人
Swedish.
- 他是做什么的 - 拉手风琴
- What does he do? - Plays the accordion.
- 当作职业吗 - 不 他有个小农场
- As a profession? - No. He owns a smallholding.
- 多小 - 我又没量过
- How small? - I haven't measured it.
莱斯利 别这么无礼
Leslie, don't be saucy!
尼斯 杰弗里
Niece! Geoffrey!
- 路易莎在这座岛上有个情郎 - 天啊
- Louisa has a beau, here on the island. - Oh!
真让人激动
How exciting!
我想严肃声明
I want us to make it
这是一个错误
quite clear that this is a mistake.
莱斯利都同意了
Even Leslie agrees,
而他的头脑都不怎么灵光
and he's not the sharpest knife in the drawer.
如果他们感情认真了
If it becomes serious,
她就会把家定居在这里了
she'll want to keep the family here forever.
BBC新闻就要播了
BBC News will be on soon.
小伙子 快一点
Hurry up, there's a chap.
莱斯利 帮我拿一个脚凳
Ah, Leslie, bring me a footstool, dear.
我感觉我的足弓越来越塌了
I can feel my fallen arches falling even further.
谢谢
Thank you.
格里 这种交通工具可是一种退步啊
Gerry, this is a terrible step backwards in transport.
在这座岛上行走
Sally's really useful for
萨莉很有用的 斯文就有一头
getting around the island. Sven's got one.
德雷尔女士 我一定要
Mrs Durrells, I must
对那次部分裸体的不幸事件
apologise again about the unfortunate incident
- 再次道歉 - 没关系 斯皮罗斯 真的
- with the partial nudity. - It's fine, Spiro. Really.
我什么都没看见 就是一团模糊
I saw nothing. It was a blur.
你要干什么 不用管我
Ti thes? Ase me!
这是本地的一种美食...
Now this is a local delicacy...
我要怎... 我不能...
What am I... I can't...
不好意思
Apologies.
没关系 一点关系都没有
Oh, it's fine. Absolutely fine.
- 西奥 - 格里
- Theo! - Gerry!
莱斯利很生气 因为她晚上在他头顶排了便
Leslie's cross cos she pooed on his head in the night.
习惯它还需要一段时间适应 不是吗
Well, it can take some getting used to, huh?
它们很虚弱
They're really weak.
恐怕要想变得强壮 它们需要吃肉
I fear to get stronger, they need meat.
我知道
I know.
我向我的朋友 瓦杜卡基斯太太提起了你
I mentioned you to my friend, Mrs Vadrukakis,
- 她对生态保护很感兴趣 - 那是什么
- who is interested in conservation. - What's that?
动物学的一个新分支
A new branch of zoology,
阻止我们破坏栖息地
to stop us tampering with our habitat
或是将某一物种赶尽杀绝
or hunting species to extinction.
我有一封英国来信 是给拉里的
Oh, I have a letter from England ford Larry.
邮递员乔治斯说很重要
The postman Georgios says it's important.
我担心他知道了
I worry that he knows.
话说回来 我为什么要给他送信
And actually, why am I delivering his letters?
你最好从门缝下塞进去
You might want to slide it under the door.
拉里的女朋友在这儿
Larry's girlfriend's here
他们... 没事就交配
and they're... copulating a lot.
好吧
Right.
你们的邮递员真勤奋
Hm... You have a very diligent postman.
从英国来的
From England.
出版商寄来的
Publishers.
"很抱歉 我们不能发表你的小说"
'We regret we are unable to publish your novel.'
拉里 亲爱的
Oh, Larry, baby.
没关系 是他们没眼光
It's OK. More fool them.
你们来科孚想看看什么
So, what would you like to see on Corfu?
这里的景致... 美不胜收
The scenery is... stunning.
天气有点热... 不适合出行
It's a little... hot for movement.
- 我们可以去游泳 - 我已经不游了
- We could go swimming. - I no longer swim.
毕竟 你的表亲弗兰克淹死了
Your cousin Frank drowned, of course.
我们又不会像他一样 跑战舰上去了
Well, I'll tell you what, we won't go on a warship like he did.
"由于在这些场合下 需要有礼节
'Owing to the need for propriety on these occasions,
所以准备一个礼物..."
it was felt that a gift of...'
我虽然不是上帝 但是...
I am not God, but...
要有光
let there be light!
- 早上好 马戈 - 你好
- Good morning, Margo. - Hello.
- 伯爵夫人呢 - 在休息
- Where's the Countess? - Resting.
她今天稍感不适
She's feeling fragile.
啊 我知道 一定是宿醉了
Ah, I know what that means. Hung over.
不 她过去也时常感到不适 心情低落
No. She has a history of fragility and dark moods
吃最昂贵的巧克力都不能缓解
which even the most expensive chocolates won't alleviate.
所以今天你可以陪伴我
So, today you can be my companion.
我离开很久了 给我讲讲英国的近况
I've been away a long time. Tell me what's happening in England.
我们离开的时候
Well, when we left,
斜切裙正流行
bias-cut dresses were all the rage.
还有发型 我要给你讲讲发型吗
Hair... Shall I tell you about hair?
快讲快讲 越详细越好
Immediately, and in great detail.
格里 这是我给你提到的瓦杜卡基斯太太
Gerry. This is Mrs Vadrukakis, whom I mentioned.
你好
Hello!
我听说你和我与西奥一样 对野生动物很热衷
I hear you are as passionate about wildlife as me and Theo.
- 是的 他教了我很多东西 - 路易莎
- Yes, he's taught me so much. - Louisa!
我知道你更喜欢和朋友在一起
I have no doubt you'd prefer the company of a friend,
但是今晚 我希望大家都能聚在这里
but I wish to see everyone gathered here this evening.
妈妈
Mother?
这是瓦杜卡基斯太太
This is Mrs Vadrukakis.
哦 你好
Oh, hello!
你好 我很想建立一个
Hello. Erm, I'm keen to start
皇家防止虐待动物协会的翻版
a version of the RSPCA.
在这里 动物们经常被虐待
Animals are often treated so badly here.
- 格里 你愿意帮忙吗 - 很乐意
- Gerry, would you help? - I'd love to.
也许你和家人也愿意尽一份力
And perhaps you and your family would help as well?
是的 当然了
Yes, of course, yes,
前提是我没被它们先杀了
if I'm not busy dangling from a rope for murder.
拜托了 亲爱的 去看看书吧
For God's sake, darling, stick your face into a school book.
正如你们所见 我的母亲最近压力很大
My mother's under a bit of pressure, as you can see.
我并不习惯做演讲
I don't make a habit of giving speeches,
但我对这个家庭的现状很担忧
but I'm distressed by what this family's become.
你父亲要是在这儿就好了
Would that your father were here now.
这里可不是抚养儿女的好地方
This is no place to bring up a family.
杰拉尔德现在就是个野孩子
Gerald is now a wild animal.
马戈似乎成了个花钱雇来的小丑
Margo seems to be some sort of paid jester.
莱斯利两次触碰法律底线
Leslie has twice been in trouble with the law.
曾经是伯恩茅斯体面的房地产经纪人的拉里
And Larry, once a respectable Bournemouth estate agent,
成了一个失败的淫棍作家
is now a debauchee and failed writer.
接下来我能描述一下你吗
Can I describe you next?
你们所有人都被一个迷恋上
All of you guided by a mother
拉手风琴的牧羊人的母亲所引领
enmeshed with a squeezebox-playing goatherd.
但你们还有希望 你们现在回家
But all is not lost. You will come home now.
我会掏钱让格里去一家好的英国寄宿学校
I will pay for Gerry to go to a good English boarding school.
帮马戈和莱斯利获得稳定的工作
I will help Margo and Leslie into secure careers.
而且 既然我终有一天要去世
And as I won't live forever,
路易莎 我会留给你一笔钱
Louisa, I will give you a sum of money,
或许留座房子
or perhaps a house,
让你过上稳定的新生活
for you to create a solid base for a new life.
谢谢你 赫尔迈厄尼姑妈
Thank you, Aunt Hermione.
我会好好考虑一下的
I will give that careful thought.
你为什么让老巫婆说那些话
Why did you let the old witch say all that?
因为我一直在欺骗自己
Because I've been fooling myself.
在现实生活中 那就是人们的真实面目
Back in the real world, that is what people are
- 和真实想法 - 我们过的就是现实生活
- and that is what people think. - This is real!
并不是 这个房子是租的
No, it's not! It's rented,
我们还付不起租金 搞不好哪天就没了
if we could afford the rent, and it's fleeting.
她说得对 我教育子女太随意
She's right. I've been playing at parenting.
我们迟早得回家
And sooner or later we are
过回之前的生活
going to have to go home and resume our lives.
事情不是这样的
It doesn't work like that.
我们在这里过的每一天都无比真实
Every day is real, here more than anywhere.
- 我们需要她 拉里 - 我们不需要
- We need her, Larry! - We don't!
你只是被她说得冲昏了头
You just let her get under your skin.
亲爱的 每个人的生活中都有一个
Darling, everyone has somebody in their lives
比他们更强大 要去听从的人
who is more powerful that they answer to...
你的父母 你的老板
your parent, your boss,
你的职业 或是你信奉的神
your calling, your God,
对我来说 就是赫尔迈厄尼姑妈
and I have Aunt Hermione.
不管这听起来有多糟
And as awful as it sounds,
她在里面说的那些话 我自己都想过
everything that she just said in there I've thought myself.
恕我直言 她有很多家底
And to be blunt, she has a lot of family money
而我不能接受
and I can't bear the thought
我的任何一个孩子穷一辈子
of any of you children being poor forever.
别乱搞
哦 你可真养眼
Oh... Well, you're a sight for sore eyes.
- 我有那么帅吗 - 特别英俊
- Remind me, is that good? - Oh, it's very good.
出什么事了
Is something wrong?
我那吓人的姑妈 她知道我们的事了
My scary aunt. She knows about us.
我本来还想装作是个毛驴商人
And I was going to pretend to be a travelling donkey salesman.
我想你
I've missed you.
我也想你
And I've missed you.
因为我已经想好了...
Because I have decided...
我爱你
I love you.
那真是太好了
Well, that's good...
因为我也爱你
because I love you too.
好了 我要...
Right, I am going to...
- 我们的客人呢 - 在卧室
- Where are our guests? - In the bedrooms.
三个人占了三间卧室
Three persons, three bedrooms.
当我们这里是酒店吗
Ti to kaname etho? Hotel!
就算要拖着去 我也要展示给他们
I am going to show them, even if I have to drag them,
科孚是集美景热恋以及文化的天堂
that Corfu is a haven for beauty and love and culture.
祝你好运吧
Good luck.
我想在马夫罗达琪别墅结束这段旅程
And I'd like to end the tour at the Villa Mavrodaki.
不行
No!
你的姑妈把我叫做花钱雇来的小丑 虽然不太懂什么意思
Your aunt called me a paid jester! Whatever that is.
那就更有必要把伯爵夫人介绍给她
Well, all the more reason to show her the magnificent library
展现她宏伟的图书馆
and appeal to her snobbery
来满足她那势利眼
by introducing her to an actual countess.
行吧
Oh, all right.
我们讨论了我被拒绝的事情
We've discussed my rejection
我决定放弃写作
and I've decided I'm giving up writing,
事实上 放弃一切跟智力有关的事情
in fact, the intellect in all its forms.
- 拉里 别傻了 - 你知道为什么吗
- Oh, don't be silly, Larry. - You know why?
因为很明显 艺术是被一些蠢货管理的
Because art is clearly run by buffoons
被铜臭味都污染了
and tainted by misguided notions of commercialism.
如果是那样的话 确实令人不快
Well, if that's true, it's beastly.
我要开始从事特别男子气概的事了
I'm throwing myself into manly things...
就像莱斯利一样 但比他更好
like Leslie, but better.
- 那么 什么东西需要维修 - 这座房子
- So, what needs mending? - The house.
还是给他缩小一下范围吧
Well, let's narrow it down for him a bit.
厕所房顶
Er... the lavatory roof?
好
Good.
今晚很难过吧
Tough night?
当拉里要讨论事情的时候
When Larry discusses something,
他真的会很严肃地讨论
he really discusses it.
- 我们一般就直接跑开 - 我下次也试试
- We usually run away. - I'll try that next time.
你还见过比这更蓝的天吗
Have you ever seen a bluer sky?
我们应该见过吧 是不是 亲爱的
I think we have, haven't we, dear?
是的 我们应该见过
Yes, I think we have.
你要是把我剖开
If you cut me open,
你会发现我身体里有英国国旗
you find the Union Jack inside.
我爱英国人 他们行为举止很赞
I love the British. Perfect manners.
总是冲在战争前线 一直坚守到最后
Always first in the war... and the last to leave.
好好看路 司机
Eyes on the road, driver.
第一站 我们的朋友西奥多·斯迪芬奈兹的家
First stop, the home of our great friend, Theodore Stephanides.
走开啊
Go on! Shoo!
- 你们外国人喜欢羊 - 是的
- Your foreigner loves his sheep. - Yes!
请原谅我房间里有些杂乱
Please forgive the disarray.
我沉浸在研究双神经软体海洋动物中了
I lost myself in a study of the marine mollusc amphineura.
都是些迷人的生物 你看不出来它们的头部
Fascinating creatures. They have no identifiable head
也没有脑神经节 然而它们配备了...
and no cerebral ganglion, obviously. Yet they are armed...
我要不要去泡点咖啡
Shall I make some coffee?
它们吃岩石上的藻类
They scrape algae from rocks.
我还可以接着介绍 那就继续吧
I could go on. In fact I will.
博物馆似乎关门了
The museum seems to be shut.
真是太可惜了
Which is such a shame,
里面满是引人入胜的工艺品
because it's full of spellbinding artefacts.
好吧 我继续坐中间
That's fine. I'll go in the middle again.
- 我必须要坐在窗边 - 她有幽闭恐怖症
- I have to be by the window. - She has claustrophobia.
- 没错 - 这可是敞篷车啊
- Yes, I do. - In an open-top car?
我们现在能回家了吗
Might we go home now?
除非你们开始享受这段旅程
Not until you start enjoying yourself.
你又把锤子掉进马桶了吗
Aw! Did you drop your hammer in the lavatory again?
这该死的杂务活
This handyman crap!
我需要正经的工作 我要去斯文家
I need proper work. I'm going to Sven's.
他肯定高兴得不得了
Oh, he'll be so delighted.
- 斯文 - 拉里
- Sven. - Larry.
- 这里是你经营的吗 - 不是
- Did you run here? - No.
哦
Oh.
听着 我打算放弃... 写那些破烂书了
Listen, I'm going to give up this... writing nonsense.
我想做一些正经工作 工钱你随意付
I want to do some proper work. Just pay me what you can.
- 什么都不付 - 好吧
- Nothing. - Fine.
好 把这个坑挖好
Good. Finish this hole.
有很多树要种
Lots of trees to plant.
别光站着不动手啊
You missed your hands, I think.
你们这些外国人啊 就是...
The thing about your foreigner is...
闭嘴
Shut up!
下一站 马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人的别墅
Next stop, the villa of the Countess Mavrodaki!
- 天使 我下班后见你 - 现在就行啊
- Angel, I will see you after work. - Now is good.
- 不 现在不行 - 不不 现在很好啊
- No, now is bad. - No, no, now is very good.
丹尼斯进城的时候 我来掌管这房子
I'm in charge of the house while Dennis is in town.
那我们去大床上蹦蹦跳跳吧
Well, let us jump on the big bed, huh?
你是八岁小孩吗
What are you, eight?
不管怎样 伯爵夫人在里面
Anyway, the Countess is inside.
伯爵夫人是我们的私交 我们互换长袍穿
You know, the Countess is a personal friend. We exchanged gowns.
她是法国人
She's French.
姑妈 尽管你对马戈的工作持怀疑态度
You know, despite your doubts about Margo's job, Aunt,
她终于对这件事认真起来了
she's finally taking something seriously
值得赞扬
and she deserves to be applauded.
我总是乐于承认错误 前提是我有错
I'm always willing to admit mistakes, if... I make any.
有人吗
Hello?
去图书馆吧 马戈经常在里面给伯爵夫人读书
The library. Margo often reads to the Countess in there.
放开 我听见了尖叫声
Let go. I heard screaming.
- 是鸡叫 - 才不是
- It was a chicken. - It wasn't a chicken!
让房间里进点光吧
Let's have some light in here!
天啊 他们已经来了
Oh, God, they're here already.
- 我在花园里忙呢 - 是啊 我们看到了
- I was busy in the garden. - Yes, yes, we saw.
伯爵夫人叫你
The Countess needs you.
马戈来了
It's Margo.
一切都会没事的
It's going to be fine.
你要知道 我没有疯
I'm not mad, you know.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
那些人是谁
Who were those people?
我的亲戚
My relatives.
他们才疯了
Now they are mad.
- 它们怎么了 - 西奥认为它们需要吃肉
- What's wrong with it? - Theo thinks they need meat.
- 吃什么肉 - 老鼠啊 或是禽类
- What do they eat? - Mice, birds, generally.
这附近有很多麻雀 我去打几只
There's loads of sparrows around. I'll shoot some.
会不会麻烦你了
Would that be any trouble?
没事 我就是干这个的
No. It's what I do.
感谢你开车带我们 斯皮罗斯
Thank you for driving us, Spiro.
不客气 德雷尔女士
You are welcome, Mrs Durrell.
我希望我很充分地看了路
I hope my eyes were sufficiently on the road.
那是谁
Who's that?
瓦杜卡基斯太太 养动物的那个
Mrs Vadrukakis. The animal lady.
- 差点打中 - 格里
- Nearly got one! - Gerry?
- 该死 可恶的小混蛋 - 太可惜了
- Damn. Little bastards. - Bugger.
不要 住手
No! Stop!
抱歉 我不知道你是谁
Sorry, I don't know who you are,
但是你有点妨碍到我了
but you're sort of in the way here.
抱歉 瓦杜卡基斯太太
Sorry, Mrs Vadrukakis,
我们这样是为了喂我的小猫头鹰
we're doing it because of my baby owls.
这是谋杀啊
This is murder!
如果真是这样 那监狱里可就要满了
In that case, I think the jails are going to be rather full.
如果你就是这么保护环境的 我为你感到羞耻
If this is your idea of conservation, I'm ashamed of you.
德雷尔女士
Mrs Durrell!
他就是个小野蛮人
He is a little savage!
你应该为自己感到羞愧
You should be ashamed of yourself.
谁快把我一枪崩了吧
Somebody shoot me please.
你完全忽视了我的建议 非但没有准备离开
You have ignored my advice and, rather than prepare to leave,
还把我们一同拉入你困境的深渊
you have dragged us deeper into your mire.
我们现在全部离开 把你的东西寄过来
We will all leave now. Have your possessions sent on.
这不公平
But that's not fair.
我本来不想说这个的
I have held back from saying this,
但作为家里的长辈
but as senior family member,
我在法律上有权利 接管杰拉尔德的监护权
I have legal grounds to claim custody of Gerald.
什么
What?
我从来没想过要孩子
I've never craved children of my own,
但是我很乐意通过律师来养一个
but I am quite willing to acquire one through my lawyers
因为你没能力来提供一个安全的生长环境
as you seem incapable of providing a secure home.
我们这就准备走...
We will pack...
希望你也能和我们一起
and I expect you to do the same.
等等
Wait!
我觉得你该走了
I think it's time you left.
你住宾馆更高兴
You'll be happier in a guest house.
我会把你的东西寄过去
I'll send your possessions on,
如果杰弗里和普鲁也这么招人讨厌
along with Geoffrey and Prue
就一块寄去
if they're as sour as you.
斯皮罗斯去哪儿了
Where's Spiro?
- 我开车带你去 - 你犯了一个大错
- I'll drive you myself. - You're making a dreadful mistake.
我宁愿自己犯错 也不愿让你在这里指手画脚
I'd rather make my own mistakes than have you make them for me.
你再那样威胁我试试
Don't you ever, ever threaten me like that again.
我宁可拽着我的孩子
I will haul my children
去地球最偏远的角落
off to the most distant corner of the earth
也不会把他们拱手相让
rather than surrender them to you or anybody else.
喂 停下
Hey! Stop! Stop!
妈妈借用一下你的车
Mum's borrowed your motor car.
没人能借我的车
Nobody borrows my motor car!
别担心 她的驾驶技术挺好
Don't worry, she's a very, very good driver.
至少十年前还不错
Or at least she was ten years ago.
她一向雷厉风行 对吧
She doesn't saunter along, does she?
慢一点 我都要晕车了
Slow down, you're making me ill!
路易莎
Louisa!
好吧 让我们好好想想
Right... Let's think about this.
你打算怎么办
Well, what are you going to do?
我打算安静地... 坐在...
I am going to sit... calmly...
你的旁边...
with you, as you're here...
然后等别人过来
and wait... for someone to come by.
尽管你对斯皮罗斯很粗鲁
And even though you were very rude to Spiro,
我确定吃他一颗糖不会生气的
I'm sure he won't begrudge you a sweet.
难道还要我提醒你
Do I have to tell you how
我们离坠崖身亡有多近吗
close we are to plummeting to our deaths?
看 那里
Oh! There.
我们身披铠甲的骑士到了 不过也许是死神
Our knight in shining armour. Or possibly the Grim Reaper.
他们从路上冲下去了
Ehei figi apo to dromo
需要你的帮助
kai hreiazomaste to gaidaro sou na to travixoume.
那些英国人还在车里
Oi Englezoi einai akoma mesa.
光着身子是挺好 直到苍蝇围着你转
Oh... Nudity's all well and good until the flies get you.
你让你的家人不要担心我的...
You will reassure your family about my...
小插曲
dark moments?
没问题 这是什么时候开始的
Of course. When did they start?
在我丈夫去世之后
After my husband died.
生活总是建立在另一个人的身边
One builds a life around a person.
也许人们不该这么做
Perhaps one shouldn't.
在他们去世之后...
And then they are gone...
陪伴你的只剩下了空气
and you're left clutching the air.
母亲说 父亲去世之后
Mother says when Daddy died,
- 她都想跳进坟墓陪伴他 - 天啊
- she wanted to jump into the grave with him. - Oh!
然后她开始掉头发
And then her hair started falling out.
- 真不知道哪个更糟糕 - 你们都还好吗
- I don't know which is worse. - Is everything all right?
是的
Yes.
谢谢你 马戈 你可以回家了
Thank you, Margo. You can go home.
好了 你的脸色不太好
There. You're looking a funny colour,
但没什么大碍
but you're going to be fine.
这回了英国根本不会发生
This wouldn't happen in the Home Counties.
在这儿也不会 因为只有我才能开这辆车
It doesn't happen here either, because only I drive the car!
你没事 真是谢天谢地
Oh! Thank the Lord you're safe!
我给杰弗里说 "我们怎么把尸体带回去啊"
I said to Geoffrey, 'How will we get the bodies home?'
- 简直是噩梦 - 我们没事 真的
- Nightmare! - We're fine. Really.
- 谢谢你 - 德雷尔女士 不要再这样了
- Thank you. - Mrs Durrells, don't do that again.
我很抱歉 斯皮罗斯
I'm so sorry, Spiro.
你身上一股我那方向盘味
You smell of my steering wheel.
包含两样我最喜欢的东西
Two of my favourite things!
等一下
Stop.
我在这里有工作 天使 我不想丢了饭碗
I have a job here, Angel, and I want to keep it.
我和你的工作哪个更重要
Which is more important? Me or your job?
我的工作
My job.
你刚刚是跺脚了吗
Did you just actually stamp your foot?
伯爵夫人生了很大的病 我一直在帮忙
The Countess has a serious illness and I've been trying to help.
伯爵夫人告诉了我事情经过
The Countess told me what happened.
是的 我很抱歉
Yes, I'm sorry.
你怎敢抛弃她 跟你的情夫寻欢作乐
How dare you abandon her to cavort with your fancy man!
我们没寻欢 而且... 他也没那么有情调
Nobody cavorted, and... he really isn't that fancy.
走吧 离开这里
Just go away. Leave.
我是怎么想的啊
What was I thinking?
差点把我们俩都害死了
I could have killed us both,
那之后我那些可怜...
and then how would my, my poor...
一团糟的孩子们该怎么办
messed-up children have coped?
幸亏你在这儿
Thank God you're here.
我不知道该做什么
I... I don't know what I'm doing.
在我乱下结论之前
Erm, before I jump to any conclusions,
你是不是在系鞋带
are you, er, tying your shoelace?
我是想问你 愿不愿意嫁给我
I am asking you if you want to marry me.
我会考虑考虑的
I'll think about it.
西奥 最糟糕的事情发生了
Theo, the most terrible thing's happened.
我和莱斯利在一起
I was with Leslie and,
然后你也知道他拿着枪...
you know how he is with guns...
瓦杜卡基斯太太告诉了我事情经过
Mrs Vadrukakis told me what happened.
她感觉... 我能替你说吗
She feels... May I speak for you?
可以
Ah, yes.
她感觉自己一怒之下 对你有些太严厉了
She feels she was somewhat hard on you in the heat of the moment.
瓦杜卡基斯太太 我之前
Mrs Vadrukakis, I didn't
没有想清楚 但我现在明白了
really think about it before, but I have now.
我保证以后尽可能地保护动物
I promise to conserve animal life wherever possible.
谢谢你 格里
Thank you, Gerry.
拉里 你怎么瘸了
Larry! Oh, you're limping!
你一定想谈谈吧
I expect you'll want to talk about it.
听着... 我很抱歉
Listen... I'm sorry.
- 怎么了 - 我之前太傻了
- For what? - For being an idiot.
还是面对现实吧 我只能做一名作家
Let's face it, I'm only ever going to be a writer.
- 充满男子气概的工作不顺利吗 - 是啊
- Oh, did the manly work not go very well? - No.
让我来安慰安慰你吧...
Let me make it better...
真不要脸
Cheeky!
鲁格勒斯雅 我听说路易莎的事了
Lugaretzia, I heard Louisa.
- 她还活着 - 那就好
- She's alive. - Oh, right.
- 佛罗伦斯 - 路易莎
- Florence! - Louisa!
- 你差点死了 - 是啊
- You nearly died! - Well, yes,
- 但是发生了很有趣的事情 - 什么
- but, erm, something really interesting has happened. - What?
我修好了发电机
I've fixed the generator!
我的新闻是
So, erm, my news.
呃... 斯文向我求婚了
Erm... Sven has asked me to marry him.
- 你打算怎么回复他 - 谁知道呢
- What are you going to say? - God knows.
拜托了 德雷尔
Stop, please, Durrells.
够了 别光顾着爱爱了
Enough! No more love!
我对自己在车里的行为感到很不安
I am uneasy at my conduct in the motor car,
却被你的折服了
and impressed by yours.
你有原则地捍卫自己的孩子 很了不起
And your principled defence of your children.
但你开车的时候没能体现出来
Though less so by your driving.
是的
Yes.
我仍然坚信 这不是抚养儿女的好地方
I still believe this isn't the best place to raise a family,
但我尊重你的选择
but I accept that the choice must be yours.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望自己给别人的印象可以不那么严厉
I wish I cut a less stern figure.
说实话 路易莎 我很想念你...
If I'm honest, I miss you, Louisa...
还有你的孩子
and the children.
那是我尝试让你回家的强硬手段
This was my heavy-handed attempt to make you come home.
你要是也跟普鲁和杰弗里
You'd do the same if you spent
一起呆那么长时间 你也会这么做的
as much time as I do with Prue and Geoffrey.
我们喜欢这里 姑妈
We like it here, Auntie.
我现在明白了
I see that now.
也理解你为什么会喜欢上...
And how you might be attracted to your...
牧羊人吗
Goatherd?
没错
Indeed.
"在水灾过后
'There was an explosion
煤矿发生了一起爆炸
at the colliery following earlier flooding.
英国计划扩大空军规模至之前三倍
Britain plans to triple the size of its air force
来应对德国的军备 首相..."
in response to German re-armament. Prime Minister...'
好哇
Hooray!
已经过去86分钟了 我需要你的回答
It's been 86 minutes. I have to have your answer.
斯文 请演奏一下你的手风琴
Sven, please play your accordion.
还是不了吧
I'd rather not.
- 那你为什么要带来 - 有道理
- So why did you bring it? - Fair point.
亲爱的 我不是在背叛你的父亲
Darling, I'm not betraying your father.
你会为我高兴的 也会为你高兴
He would be happy for me. And for you.
我知道 我只是很想念他
I know. I just miss him.
那么 伯爵夫人怎么样了
So, how was the Countess?
她很忧伤 收到了惊吓 丹尼斯对我不太高兴
She was sad, shaken. Dennis wasn't very happy with me.
也许是时候
It might be time for me to
我成熟一点 承担责任了
grow up a bit and learn some responsibility.
说来也好笑
You know, it's funny,
因为我正想反其道而行之
cos I was just feeling like going the other way.
我开始喜欢吃鱿鱼了
I'm coming round to calamari.
我们要不要再冒险加个橄榄
Shall we go mad and risk an olive?
各位 计划有些变动
Everyone. Change of plan.
我要重拾我作家的职业 接着做知识分子
I'm going back to being a writer and an intellectual.
太棒了
Yes!
- 它们开始吃东西了 - 那些猫头鹰
- They're feeding! - The owls!
我可以很确信地说
I can confidently say that
拉里是世界上最差的农民
Larry is probably the worst farmer on the planet.
不过他写书的时候
Although when he writes about it,
可能会把自己写得很厉害
I think he'll probably be rather better.
听着 斯文 关于你的求婚
Um... Listen, Sven, about your proposal.
就是...
Just...
我愿意
Yes.